Rajdip Bhattacharya

rajdipbhattacharya973@gmail.com

Desired Job Profile

With 21 years of enriching experience in the industry, I am looking forward to explore new opportunity in the culinary industry

My Specialties include Multi cuisine and Modern Fusion cuisine

I look forward to utilizing and improving my skills in managing kitchen staff, creating new menu, controlling food costs, making menu merchandising & evaluating the competition.

I know myself to possess a competitive spirit and I believe in the significance of motivating the staffand building team spirit.

Personal Information

Father's Name: Late Mr. Ashok Ranjan Bhattacharya Address: 3A Kirtibas Lane, Kolkata 700026

Date of Birth 19'° sept 1977
Mobile No 9007930747
9903199636

Education Qualification

10" Std, St. Helen, Kolkata, I.C.S.E, 2'd DiviSion (1994-95)

12'^ Std, St. Helen, Kolkata, I.S.C, 1" Division (1996-97)

Professional Qualification

Diploma in Hotel & Motel Management from Educational institute of American Hotel and Motel Association, Washington D.C,U.S.A with Honours (2000) February.

3 yrs. Diploma in Hotel & Catering Management from Institute of Advanced Management (I.A.M), Kolkata, India (2000) June

B.A in Hospitality Management from Robert Gordon

University, Aberdeen, Scotland, U.K (2000) May

Industrial Placement

10 weeks of Vocational Training in Taj Bengal, Kolkata, India

(1997-98)

4 weeks of Industrial Training in Hotel Hindustan

International, Kolkata, India (1998)

24 weeks of Industrial Training in Clarks Amer, Jaipur, India

(1998-99)

Professional Experience

Worked as Hotel Operation Trainee, Food Production Department at ITC MAURYA SHERATON DELHI, Park Sheraton Hotel & Towers, Chennai India(2000-02)

Worked as Head Chef in Woodlands Group of Restaurants (South Indian Specialty Restaurant), London, U.K(2002-04)

Worked as Chef De Partie in Intercontinental Group, Holiday Inn, Mayfair, London ,U.K (2004 January – 2012 December)

Transferred (Inter Hotel Transfer) as Junior Sous Chef in Holiday Inn, Bristol, London U.K (2006 September – 2009)

Transferred (Inter Hotel Transfer) as Sous Chef in Holiday Inn, Hyde Park, London U.K (2009 November - 2012 December

Worked as Head Chef in Laporte Des Indes (The Gateway to India)London (part of BLUE ELEPHANTGROUP)-Indian restaurant with a twist of French Cuisine (2013January – 2014 April)

Worked as EXECUTIVE SOUS CHEF INDISMART

HOTEL

KOLKATA (I.I.H.M.HOTEL EDUCATIONAL GROUP) from 11.07.2014 till February 2021

Member of JUDGEPANNEL 2014-2019 YOUNG
OLIYMPIAD CHEF INDIA, along With CHEF SUJAN MEKHERJEE
(EXECUTIVECHEF TAJ COROMANDAL CHENNAI), CHEF SANJAY KAK (EX
EXECUTIVE CHEF TAJ MAHAL MUMBAI) CHEF SHAUN KENWORTHEE.
(CELEBRITY CHEF THE PARK HOTEL KOLKATA)
CHEF SANJIB KAPOOR (CELEBRITY CHEF)

Employee of the Month July2004, HolidayInn, Mayfair

,London,U.K

D.D.A-Confidence to Serve All-Training in

Intercontinental

Group, Holiday Inn, Mayfair

Foundation certificate in Food Hygiene London, U.K

INDIA(CHENNAI)

Chartered Institute of Environmental Health

Fire & Life Saver Certificate ,ITC Park Sheraton, Chenni

Won 1st prize and Best CHEF Award

intra-college I Innovative Food Contest Organized by Nestle Group India, 2000

Position Applied for CHEF DECUISINE/SOUS CHEF